how an attacker would try and create
something nasty, something malicious.
How would they go about that?
>> The most important one is trust because
you want to trust either a skill or an
MCP server. You have an MCP server with
the reasoning of, "Okay, I'm able to
access your calendar and see what your
appointments are for today." Great. It
works. You implement it, does nothing
weird, but then we update the skill and
then we put something extra. We put a
side effect in or we return instead of
just your calendar items, we return it
an instruction. But you already trusted
that specific function in it. But from
now on, even maybe silently, it will
operate in a different way and that side
effect might be able to offload
credentials or install a binary or name
it.
So, that is one thing, the trust. Trust
is is is super important. Then um most
of these things, especially specifically
in skills, will be obfuscated. Yeah. And
obfuscation can be done in Unicode
encoding. Some some parts of of of
the Unicode spectrum are not visible
even for the human eye or for
if you read it in a text editor. Mhm. Um
but are readable instructions for an
LLM.
Um it can also be something that is
named in a different way, is is base 64
encoded or even maybe simply encrypted.
Um so, that obfuscation pattern that you
won't obviously see it.
Uh yeah, that is that is something that
that is something as well. And
obviously, if we can do that, we can
make these attacks in steps.
If we're able to you trust me, um I add
something in that that skill or that MCP
server, um I may be able to disable some
of your some of your security guards or
or guardrails or maybe even rewrite your
guardrails. And in the next step, I will
do the attack. So, it's not it's not a
one-shot thing in most cases. Trust is
an interesting thing as well because
essentially, when we talk about trust,
very often these skills hosted just in a
GitHub repo.
>> Yeah. And it goes back to that very same
problem of open-source code. Yep. You're
now trusting someone.
Essentially, you don't know where they
live, you don't know what their
background is. You don't know, you know,
what security processes they follow,
what what security what software hygiene
they have in and around their project.
But because it does something that a
developer of a company wants to use,
they download it and they pull that
directly into their environment,
potentially, you know, using that, maybe
checking it in or maybe adding it into
that others will also use that, you
know, sharing across the company.
And it's it's so dangerous. Um we don't
have those similar checks up until now.
How would a user
uh use Snyk, I guess, directly and then
we'll talk about within the test or
registry
uh to to identify where these malicious
skills and MCPs are? Yeah. So, say you
have skills installed in Cloud or any of
the other other well-known um agents
that you can that you can use
for skills or for MCPs. Um we have we
have a Basically, it's on it's it's on
GitHub.
Funny enough, I definitely trust it.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
There's a company behind it and we we
definitely want to want to retain our
um
our our good profile of of we're helping
people. But if you go to to what is it
Git GitHub .com/snyk/ what is it agent
agent-scan?
Um that is the Snyk agent scan and you
can basically use it. It's a Python
project which you can launch with UV.
Mhm. And then it will scan the most
well-known uh positions on your local
machine, for instance, to like the doc
cloud library where your skills can be
stored. And same for the MCPs. And if
you have a specific location where your
skills are stored, you can give that in
as well and and it will and it will look
for are there anomalies there. So, this
the the scan that it that is happening
is not just one simple scan and and not
and it's not all it's not a
deterministic one thing to do.
Yeah.
>> so, there are some static scans around
that, but there are also some LLMs
involved that basically LLMs as a as a
judge. Different LLMs that look into,
"Hey, is this vulnerable, yes or no?"
And the combination of all these checks,
because there are multiple checks, will
be handed to you
in in this case uh your terminal to see
like, "Okay, this is what you have.
These um
functions in your MCP or these things in
your skill um are potentially
dangerous." And it will give you how
dangerous they are. It will give a score
to you like, "Hey, this is I will give
this a a a 0.5 because yes, potentially
this can be used. However, so it's
nuanced in such a way that it's actually
actionable for actionable for you. So,
then you know what you're having, what
kind of
um functions or what kind of skills you
deploy towards your agents.
And you can make at least um an educated
decision, do you want this, yes or no?
Do you want to uninstall the skill?
Yeah, it's it's one of those things
that, you know, it's a starting point.
You want to look at it, you want to flag
something that it believes is is but
maybe actually some of those activities
or those actions that the skill will do
is actually intentional. Uh
but it's it's about flagging the fact
that that's what it's trying to do and
it's a case of, "Okay, is this right?"
Uh and then I can make the decision of
actually, yes, I trust this or or maybe
it's the author. I look at the author
and say, "Yeah, actually, this is an
author I absolutely trust and I
I I want to use it."
>> instance, even if you create your your
your own MCPs. I created my own MCPs to
discover what kind of Java conferences
are still open and what that don't don't
want to miss a call for papers, for
instance.
>> Yeah. Um so, I have that as a as a very
small MCP and then it flagged it as,
"Hey, you are pulling in data from an
external source.
But since it's this is static data, um
the the the chance that this is really
vulnerable is quite low, but at least
you know that this is happening. And
then you can you can you can see if you
want to trust it, yes or no."